Guide to the Richard Charles Lee Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, 1960, 1980-1985, 1989-1990, n.d; Accession 1991-M-048
  - Writings of others
    - "The State of Our Cities and Suburbs in A Changing America," published by the Advisory Council of the Democratic National Committee, 1960 June (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Urban Growth in the Decade Ahead," policy paper no. 2 by the Advisory Committee on Urban and Suburban Problems, 1960 June (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Testimonies given at the Route 34 environmental impact statement hearing, Troup Junior High School, 1980 January 30 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Research in Public Policy Analysis and Management: Basic Theory, Methods and Perspectives, edited by John P. Crecine, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Catholic Elementary School Study, New Haven, Connecticut (draft), 1985 February-March (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "My Brother," by A.G. Martone: biography of a high school classmate of Richard C. Lee, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Additional Material, 1992; Accession 1993-M-050
  Extent: 1 folder
  Received from: Richard C. Lee, 1993 Feb 8
  - Interview with Richard C. Lee, conducted by Noel A. Cazenave: pertaining to Lee's participation in programs which served as precursors to the U. S. War on Poverty, 1992 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Additional Material, Accession 2001-M-010
  Conditions Governing Access
  The material is unprocessed and may contain sensitive information or be in a physical state that would prohibit use. Researchers wishing to request access should email mssa.assist@yale.edu requesting specific box numbers in order to initiate the review process, which may take several weeks.
  - Speeches, 1954-1975 (Box 1–4)
  - Inauguration ceremonies (Box 4)
  - Raw speech files (some unfoldered) (Box 4–6)
  - Wooster Square redevelopment photographs (Box 6)
  - State of the City messages (Box 7)
  - Mayoralty campaign, 1951-1961 (Box 7–9)
  - Photographs, 1948-1969 (Box 9–14)
  - Personal files, 1973-1974 (Box 14)
  - Speeches (Box 14)
  - Recent correspondence (some unfoldered) (Box 15–17)
  - Appointment books (Box 17)
  - U. S. Conference of Mayors, Hawaii, 1963 (Box 18)
  - Yale University Honorary Degree [includes photographs], 1961 June (Box 18)
  - John F. Kennedy correspondence [photocopies], 1946, 1955-1965 (Box 18)
  - Cavalierre Ufficiale dell'Ordine Al Merito della Repubblica Italiana, 1960 (Box 18)
  - Newspaper articles (Box 19)
  - Catholic elementary school study (Box 19)
  - Historical Society papers (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous files, A-R (Box 19)
  - Files A-M (Box 20)
  - Files N-Z (Box 21)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 21)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 22)
  - Speeches (Box 22–24)
  - Letters (Box 24)
  - Datebooks, 1998-1999 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence (Box 25)
  - Speeches (Box 25)
  - Eulogies (Box 25)
  - Confidential bank memoranda (Box 25)
  - Book chapters (Box 25)
  - Correspondence (Box 26)
  - Speeches (Box 26)
  - Articles (Box 26)
  - Book chapters (Box 26)
  - Files, A-C, 1985-1989 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence (Box 27)
  - Files, D-Z, 1985-1989 (Box 27)
  - Guest lists (Box 27)
  - Newspaper articles (Box 28)
  - Files, 1990s and undated (Box 28)
  - Speeches, 1980s (Box 28)
  - Newspaper articles, speeches, and correspondence, 1960-1970s (Box 29–30)
  - Miscellaneous files (Box 31)
  - Datebooks, 1991-1997 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence (Box 32)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 32)
  - Articles (Box 32)
  - Photographs (Box 32)
  - Articles, books, datebooks, speeches, and correspondence (Box 33–34)
  - Cassette tapes (approximately 50) (Box 35)
  - Albertus Magnus College lecture series, 1986 (Box 35)
  - Jonathan Edwards College class, "Role of the Mayor and the Future of the American City,", 1962 Fall (Box 35)
  - Film narration, "Kennedy and New Haven" (Box 35)
  - "John F. Kennedy in New Haven" [35mm, 2 reels], 1965 (Box 36)
  - Philadelphia-Pittsburgh trip [35mm], 1955 (Box 36)
  - "Mayor Lee Interview," New Haven Colony Historical Society Award [videotape], 1992 August 27 (Box 36)
  - Lee speech at Cosgrove Dinner, Park Plaza Hotel, 1979 November 14; Audiotape (Reel-to-reel), 8:43 minutes (Box 37)
    Existence and Location of Originals
    Original retained by donor.
    - Duplicating master, 1979 November 14; Audiocasette (Box 37D)
    - Use copy, 1974 November 4; Compact disc (Box 37U)
- Additional Material, Accession 2001-M-017
  - Speech files, 1954-1969 (Box 1)
  - Personal correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Government Center Task Force, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - New Haven audit report, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Election voting machine irregularities, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Campaign surveys, 1963-1965, 1967-1968, 1949, 1955-1959, 1963-1968, 1980 (Box 3)
- Additional Material, Circa 1954; Accession 2012-M-012
  - Campaign poster on board, "This is the Platform of the Democratic Party & "Dick" Lee", Circa 1954 (Folder 1)